<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
    xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"
    xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">
  <channel>
    <title><![CDATA[Hafta Podcast]]></title>
    <description><![CDATA[All Hafta episodes]]></description>
    <link>https://www.newslaundry.com/hafta</link>
    <image>
      <url>https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1751695551059-62a98700-bdf2-4588-911c-4f8f4d930ac3.jpeg</url>
      <title>Hafta Podcast</title>
      <link>https://www.newslaundry.com/hafta</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Python Script</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 15:42:06 GMT</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.newslaundry.com/hafta" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 08:30:55 GMT</pubDate>
    <copyright><![CDATA[All rights reserved]]></copyright>
    <language><![CDATA[en]]></language>
    <managingEditor>subscription@newslaundry.com (Newslaundry)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>subscription@newslaundry.com (Newslaundry)</webMaster>
    <category><![CDATA[News]]></category>
    <itunes:author>Newslaundry.com</itunes:author>
    <itunes:summary><![CDATA[All Hafta episodes]]></itunes:summary>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:name>Newslaundry</itunes:name>
      <itunes:email>subscription@newslaundry.com</itunes:email>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1751695551059-62a98700-bdf2-4588-911c-4f8f4d930ac3.jpeg" />
    <itunes:category text="News" />
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Hafta 544 : India’s lost tourism potential, and floods in Himachal Pradesh and Uttarakhand]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[<p><br></p><p>This week on Hafta, <em>Newslaundry</em>’s Manisha Pande, Jayashree Arunachalam and Raman Kirpal&nbsp;are joined by writer and economist Vivek Kaul and environmental journalist Hridayesh Joshi.&nbsp;</p><p><br></p><p>The episode begins with a discussion comparing India’s tourism landscape with that of Southeast Asian countries and why, despite its size, beauty and culture, India remains far behind its Asian neighbours as a global tourist destination.&nbsp;</p><p><br></p><p>Manisha draws comparisons with cleaner, better-maintained cities like Ho Chi Minh City and Bali, and questions why India continues to fall behind in basic urban infrastructure and tourist appeal.&nbsp;</p><p><br></p><p>Jayashree says, “India is unsafe for everyone. That’s why tourists are unsafe here.” Vivek adds, “In 2024, Bali got a little over 6 million foreign tourists. In 2023, they got over 5 million…Forget Goa, Bali probably gets as many tourists as all of India does.”</p><p><br></p><p>On India’s cleanliness problem, Jayashree says: “Caste is the main driver of dirt. The wealthy produce the most waste and don’t care about where it goes.” Hridayesh says, “We dump solid waste into rivers; this happens with full knowledge of officials who take bribes.”</p><p><br></p><p>On environmental degradation and the floods in Himachal Pradesh, Hridayesh warns, “We are doing everything to facilitate a disaster, not prevent one.” He explains how unchecked construction and poor planning turns natural hazards into man-made disasters.&nbsp;</p><p><br></p><p>This and a lot more. Tune in!</p><p><br></p><p><em>We have a page for subscribers to send letters to our shows. If you want to write to Hafta, </em><a href="https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast-letters" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>click here</em></a><em>. And click </em><a href="http://newslaundry.com/sena" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>here</em></a><em> to contribute to our new Sena project.</em></p><p><em>Check out the</em><a href="https://www.newslaundry.com/store?routeName=NlStore" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em> Newslaundry store</em></a><em> and flaunt your love for independent media.&nbsp;</em></p><p><br></p><p><em>Download the</em><a href="http://www.newslaundry.com/download-app" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em> Newslaundry app</em></a><em>. '</em></p><p><br></p><p><strong>Timecodes</strong></p><p>00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements</p><p>00:05:06 – Headlines&nbsp;</p><p>00:13:44 - Tourism in India and why we are lagging behind</p><p>00:57:58 - Floods in Himachal Pradesh and Uttarakhand</p><p>01:31:41 - Letters</p><p>01:45:23- Recommendations</p><p><br></p><p><em>Check out </em><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VCmV6yr5t1LHE77Xp5-cYhWrQSkhW3A8nix310MvRQU/edit?usp=sharing" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters</em></a><em>.</em></p><p><br></p><p><strong><em>Produced and recorded by Priyali Dhingra, Amit Pandey, and Anil Kumar.&nbsp;</em></strong></p><p><strong><em>Production and research assistance by Saurav Ranjan and Swastika Rajput.&nbsp;</em></strong></p><p><br></p><p><br></p>]]></description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">6868c1f43b5dc9fc2237ce73</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Newslaundry]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 06:12:08 GMT</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://feeds.acast.com/public/streams/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/episodes/6868c1f43b5dc9fc2237ce73.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="215304574"/>
      <itunes:author>Newslaundry</itunes:author>
      <itunes:summary><![CDATA[This week on Hafta, Newslaundry’s Manisha Pande, Jayashree Arunachalam and Raman Kirpal&nbsp;are joined by writer and economist Vivek Kaul and environmental journalist Hridayesh Joshi.&nbsp;The episode begins with a discussion comparing India’s tourism landscape with that of Southeast Asian countries and why, despite its size, beauty and culture, India remains far behind its Asian neighbours as a global tourist destination.&nbsp;Manisha draws comparisons with cleaner, better-maintained cities like Ho Chi Minh City and Bali, and questions why India continues to fall behind in basic urban infrastructure and tourist appeal.&nbsp;Jayashree says, “India is unsafe for everyone. That’s why tourists are unsafe here.” Vivek adds, “In 2024, Bali got a little over 6 million foreign tourists. In 2023, they got over 5 million…Forget Goa, Bali probably gets as many tourists as all of India does.”On India’s cleanliness problem, Jayashree says: “Caste is the main driver of dirt. The wealthy produce the most waste and don’t care about where it goes.” Hridayesh says, “We dump solid waste into rivers; this happens with full knowledge of officials who take bribes.”On environmental degradation and the floods in Himachal Pradesh, Hridayesh warns, “We are doing everything to facilitate a disaster, not prevent one.” He explains how unchecked construction and poor planning turns natural hazards into man-made disasters.&nbsp;This and a lot more. Tune in!We have a page for subscribers to send letters to our shows. If you want to write to Hafta, click here. And click here to contribute to our new Sena project.Check out the Newslaundry store and flaunt your love for independent media.&nbsp;Download the Newslaundry app. 'Timecodes00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements00:05:06 – Headlines&nbsp;00:13:44 - Tourism in India and why we are lagging behind00:57:58 - Floods in Himachal Pradesh and Uttarakhand01:31:41 - Letters01:45:23- RecommendationsCheck out previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters.Produced and recorded by Priyali Dhingra, Amit Pandey, and Anil Kumar.&nbsp;Production and research assistance by Saurav Ranjan and Swastika Rajput.&nbsp;]]></itunes:summary>
      <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
      <itunes:duration>01:51:43</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:image href="https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1751695551059-62a98700-bdf2-4588-911c-4f8f4d930ac3.jpeg" />
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Hafta 543 : 50 years of Emergency, voter additions in Maharashtra, Karnataka’s new bills]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>This week on Hafta, <em>Newslaundry</em>’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Jayashree Arunachalam, Raman Kirpal and Anand Vardhan are joined by senior journalist Neerja Chowdhury, <em>The News Minute</em>’s editor-in-chief Dhanya Rajendran, and <em>Newslaundry </em>reporter Sumedha Mittal.&nbsp;</p><p><br></p><p>This week marked the 50th anniversary of the Emergency and the central government’s commemoration of the event. Neerja says it was important, since most young Indians today weren’t alive during the Emergency and are unaware of its impact. But “have we learned lessons”, Abhinandan asks, and the panel has varying views.&nbsp;</p><p><br></p><p>Dhanya explains two new bills in Karnataka – one to tackle fake news, and the other criminalising hate speech. She talks about why both are problematic and what the Congress government in the state hopes to achieve.</p><p><br></p><p>The panel then discusses Sumedha’s report from Nagpur, where she found over 29,200 new voters were curiously added to the electoral rolls in Devendra Fadnavis’s constituency. This <em>Newslaundry</em> investigation has triggered a political outcry in the state, and Sumedha explains why.</p><p><br></p><p>This and a lot more. Tune in!</p><p><br></p><p><em>We have a page for subscribers to send letters to our shows. If you want to write to Hafta, </em><a href="https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast-letters" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>click here</em></a><em>. And click </em><a href="http://newslaundry.com/sena" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>here</em></a><em> to contribute to our new Sena project.</em></p><p><em>Check out the</em><a href="https://www.newslaundry.com/store?routeName=NlStore" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em> Newslaundry store</em></a><em> and flaunt your love for independent media.&nbsp;</em></p><p><br></p><p><em>Download the</em><a href="http://www.newslaundry.com/download-app" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em> Newslaundry app</em></a><em>. </em></p><p><br></p><p><strong>Song: </strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JJk0PqiVBAE&amp;t=84s" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank">U96 - Das Boot</a></p><p><br></p><p><strong>Timecodes</strong></p><p>00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements</p><p>00:03:13– Headlines&nbsp;</p><p>00:10:35 - 50 years of Emergency and its media coverage&nbsp;</p><p>00:43:25- Karnataka Misinformation and Fake News (Prohibition) Bill</p><p>01:08:38 - Voter additions in Maharashtra&nbsp;</p><p>01:21:03 - Letters</p><p>01:26:52 - Recommendations</p><p><br></p><p><em>Check out </em><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VCmV6yr5t1LHE77Xp5-cYhWrQSkhW3A8nix310MvRQU/edit?usp=sharing" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters</em></a><em>.</em></p><p><br></p><p><strong><em>Produced and recorded by Ashish Anand, Amit Pandey and Anil Kumar.&nbsp;</em></strong></p><p><strong><em>Research assistance by Swastika Rajput.&nbsp;</em></strong></p><p><strong><em>Production assistance by Saurabh and Ankit Raj.</em></strong></p>]]></description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">685f92bc653df36e7b1d4807</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Newslaundry]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 06:59:08 GMT</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://feeds.acast.com/public/streams/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/episodes/685f92bc653df36e7b1d4807.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="142217059"/>
      <itunes:author>Newslaundry</itunes:author>
      <itunes:summary><![CDATA[This week on Hafta, Newslaundry’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Jayashree Arunachalam, Raman Kirpal and Anand Vardhan are joined by senior journalist Neerja Chowdhury, The News Minute’s editor-in-chief Dhanya Rajendran, and Newslaundry reporter Sumedha Mittal.&nbsp;This week marked the 50th anniversary of the Emergency and the central government’s commemoration of the event. Neerja says it was important, since most young Indians today weren’t alive during the Emergency and are unaware of its impact. But “have we learned lessons”, Abhinandan asks, and the panel has varying views.&nbsp;Dhanya explains two new bills in Karnataka – one to tackle fake news, and the other criminalising hate speech. She talks about why both are problematic and what the Congress government in the state hopes to achieve.The panel then discusses Sumedha’s report from Nagpur, where she found over 29,200 new voters were curiously added to the electoral rolls in Devendra Fadnavis’s constituency. This Newslaundry investigation has triggered a political outcry in the state, and Sumedha explains why.This and a lot more. Tune in!We have a page for subscribers to send letters to our shows. If you want to write to Hafta, click here. And click here to contribute to our new Sena project.Check out the Newslaundry store and flaunt your love for independent media.&nbsp;Download the Newslaundry app. Song: U96 - Das BootTimecodes00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements00:03:13– Headlines&nbsp;00:10:35 - 50 years of Emergency and its media coverage&nbsp;00:43:25- Karnataka Misinformation and Fake News (Prohibition) Bill01:08:38 - Voter additions in Maharashtra&nbsp;01:21:03 - Letters01:26:52 - RecommendationsCheck out previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters.Produced and recorded by Ashish Anand, Amit Pandey and Anil Kumar.&nbsp;Research assistance by Swastika Rajput.&nbsp;Production assistance by Saurabh and Ankit Raj.]]></itunes:summary>
      <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
      <itunes:duration>01:38:43</itunes:duration>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title><![CDATA[Hafta 541: Air India crash, Manipur violence, covering crime stories ]]></title>
      <description><![CDATA[<p>This week on Hafta, <em>Newslaundry</em>’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Raman Kirpal, Manisha Pande, and Jayashree Arunachalam are joined by former Executive Director, Air India, Jitendra Bhargava, and Executive Editor of <em>The Frontier Manipur</em>, Paojel Choaba.&nbsp; </p><p><br></p><p>The episode begins with a discussion on the devastating Air India crash, where a Boeing 787 Dreamliner, carrying 242 passengers, crashed shortly after takeoff in Ahmedabad. Jitender adds, “The cockpit voice recorder and black box will decode what actually transpired between pilot and the co-pilot…and what, if anything, was said to the passengers in the last moments.” Manisha raises concerns about Boeing’s history, citing, “Boeing has actually just wrapped up a long legal case in the US where they’ve paid a billion dollars for two crashes,” though Bhargava counters, “The safety track record must prove what it is,” given the Dreamliner’s extensive operational history.</p><p><br></p><p>The panel critiques the media’s handling, with Jayashree expressing dismay: “I thought it was quite upsetting… families had found out minutes ago just as the reporters were arriving.”</p><p><br></p><p>The conversation shifts to Manipur’s ethnic conflict, with Paojel providing firsthand insights. He describes a tense peace, “The shooting has stopped, but the violence has become more internal in a way.” Over 60,000 people are displaced, and “more than 200 people have been killed.”</p><p><br></p><p>Commenting on the President's rule, he adds, “While there has been some recovery of arms under the Governor's rule, there has been no concrete positive actions to restore normalcy. But law and order has improved.” </p><p><br></p><p>The panel also discusses the murder case in Meghalaya dominating headlines throughout the week and the ethics of covering crime stories.&nbsp;</p><p><br></p><p>This and a lot more. Tune in!</p><p><br></p><p><br></p><p><br></p><p><em>We have a page for subscribers to send letters to our shows. If you want to write to Hafta, </em><a href="https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast-letters" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>click here</em></a><em>.&nbsp;</em></p><p><em>Check out the</em><a href="https://www.newslaundry.com/store?routeName=NlStore" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em> Newslaundry store</em></a><em> and flaunt your love for independent media.&nbsp;</em></p><p><br></p><p><em>Download the</em><a href="http://www.newslaundry.com/download-app" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em> Newslaundry app</em></a><em>. </em></p><p><br></p><p><br></p><p><strong>Timecodes</strong></p><p>00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements</p><p>00:02:12– Headlines&nbsp;</p><p>00:06:51 - Air India crash</p><p>00:45:28 - Announcements</p><p>00:47:48 - Manipur violence</p><p>01:17:31 - Meghalaya murder case and how crime stories should be covered</p><p>01:29:47 - Letters&nbsp;</p><p>01:38:30 - Recommendations</p><p><br></p><p><br></p><p><em>Check out </em><a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VCmV6yr5t1LHE77Xp5-cYhWrQSkhW3A8nix310MvRQU/edit?usp=sharing" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"><em>previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters</em></a><em> </em></p><p><br></p><p><strong><em>Produced by Priyali Dhingra and Amit Pandey. </em></strong></p><p><strong><em>Recorded by Ashish Anand and Anil Kumar.&nbsp;</em></strong></p><p><br></p><p><br></p><p><br></p>]]></description>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">684d2017b903c43b04184f2c</guid>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[Newslaundry]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 07:09:10 GMT</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://feeds.acast.com/public/streams/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/episodes/684d2017b903c43b04184f2c.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="210828767"/>
      <itunes:author>Newslaundry</itunes:author>
      <itunes:summary><![CDATA[This week on Hafta, Newslaundry’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Raman Kirpal, Manisha Pande, and Jayashree Arunachalam are joined by former Executive Director, Air India, Jitendra Bhargava, and Executive Editor of The Frontier Manipur, Paojel Choaba.&nbsp; The episode begins with a discussion on the devastating Air India crash, where a Boeing 787 Dreamliner, carrying 242 passengers, crashed shortly after takeoff in Ahmedabad. Jitender adds, “The cockpit voice recorder and black box will decode what actually transpired between pilot and the co-pilot…and what, if anything, was said to the passengers in the last moments.” Manisha raises concerns about Boeing’s history, citing, “Boeing has actually just wrapped up a long legal case in the US where they’ve paid a billion dollars for two crashes,” though Bhargava counters, “The safety track record must prove what it is,” given the Dreamliner’s extensive operational history.The panel critiques the media’s handling, with Jayashree expressing dismay: “I thought it was quite upsetting… families had found out minutes ago just as the reporters were arriving.”The conversation shifts to Manipur’s ethnic conflict, with Paojel providing firsthand insights. He describes a tense peace, “The shooting has stopped, but the violence has become more internal in a way.” Over 60,000 people are displaced, and “more than 200 people have been killed.”Commenting on the President's rule, he adds, “While there has been some recovery of arms under the Governor's rule, there has been no concrete positive actions to restore normalcy. But law and order has improved.” The panel also discusses the murder case in Meghalaya dominating headlines throughout the week and the ethics of covering crime stories.&nbsp;This and a lot more. Tune in!We have a page for subscribers to send letters to our shows. If you want to write to Hafta, click here.&nbsp;Check out the Newslaundry store and flaunt your love for independent media.&nbsp;Download the Newslaundry app. Timecodes00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements00:02:12– Headlines&nbsp;00:06:51 - Air India crash00:45:28 - Announcements00:47:48 - Manipur violence01:17:31 - Meghalaya murder case and how crime stories should be covered01:29:47 - Letters&nbsp;01:38:30 - RecommendationsCheck out previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters Produced by Priyali Dhingra and Amit Pandey. Recorded by Ashish Anand and Anil Kumar.&nbsp;]]></itunes:summary>
      <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
      <itunes:duration>01:49:33</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:image href="https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1749884896956-52de8abc-0f60-4a83-83fd-513e922d515e.jpeg" />
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>