<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<rss xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Newslaundry Hafta</title>
    <description>Freewheeling discussion on the news of the week from Newslaundry</description>
    <link>https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast/nl-hafta</link>
    <image>
      <url>https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1751695551059-62a98700-bdf2-4588-911c-4f8f4d930ac3.jpeg</url>
      <title>Hafta Podcast</title>
      <link>https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast/nl-hafta</link>
    </image>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <itunes:author>Newslaundry</itunes:author>
    <itunes:category text="News"/>
    <itunes:explicit>false</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:type>episodic</itunes:type>
    <itunes:image href="https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1751695551059-62a98700-bdf2-4588-911c-4f8f4d930ac3.jpeg"/>
    <item>
      <title>Hafta 553: Modi’s bonhomie with Xi &amp; Putin at Tianjin, Maratha quota protests </title>
      <description>This week on Hafta, Newslaundry’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Manisha Pande, and Shardool Katyayan are joined by Akshay Bhambri, doctoral fellow at the Institute for Chinese Studies–Harvard Yenching Institute, and Sumeet Mhaskar, professor at OP Jindal Global University.&amp;nbsp;The conversation opens with Prime Minister Narendra Modi’s visit to China for the SCO Summit – his first visit to the country since 2018 – where he held talks with Chinese President Xi Jinping and Russian President Vladimir Putin. The panel analyses the optics of the meeting, body language narratives, and India’s strategic balancing act.&amp;nbsp;Akshay argues that the Indian media’s portrayal of Chinese reactions is not actually correct, noting that Chinese social media largely framed Modi’s presence through Xi’s success in convening world leaders rather than admiration for Modi himself.“The Times of India and The Print reported that Putin and Modi’s car ride was trending on Baidu, China’s equivalent of Google. It did appear in the top 20 of Baidu’s trending list, but the conversation wasn’t really about appreciating Modi or his actions. Instead, users were more focused on how Trump might react, what this meant for Putin, and how Xi Jinping had managed to orchestrate the moment,” says Bhambri.&amp;nbsp;He also questions PM Modi’s visit with Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi.&amp;nbsp;“A big negative coming from SCO is that Modi met the right hand of Xi Jinping, Wang Yee, and all these people. When a head like the Prime Minister and president of China are meeting each other, there was no point meeting a second right hand of Xi Jinping, because that's a level below Xi Jinping.” Bhambri adds.&amp;nbsp;Abhinandan adds, “The challenge for the Indian leadership is that Trump’s unpredictability has forced everyone to realign their positions. He has shaken up the global order so dramatically that confusion is inevitable.”&amp;nbsp;Speaking on India’s foreign policy, Manisha points out, “Indian diplomats and India’s foreign policy also have a lot to answer for, because they relied too much on the supposed personal chemistry of Modi with global leaders. Serious diplomats, or mandarins as they’re called, should have calculated what could happen and what needed to be done as situations evolved. You have to work out your realignment in advance, because at the end of the day, this is a game of chess.”Sumeet explains that social hierarchy plays a crucial role in how protests are treated. When dominant castes like the Marathas mobilise, the state response is far more restrained compared to how it would react if Muslims or Dalits staged similar demonstrations. Timecodes00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements00:03:30– Headlines&amp;nbsp;00:11:59 - &amp;nbsp;PM Modi at SCO, Tianjin00:59:55- Maratha quota protest01:36:56 - Akshay &amp;amp; Sumeet’s recommendations01:43:10 - Letters01:50:28 - RecommendationsCheck out previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters.Produced by Amit Pandey with production assistant Ashish Anand and sound recordist Anil .&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <link>https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast/nl-hafta</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Sep 2025 06:13:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://feeds.acast.com/public/streams/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/episodes/68bbd10b1af371182a0250b4.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="7144882"/>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:duration>01:56:17</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:image href="https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1757156290210-933b1685-a2f6-410b-ac5a-8d5a396668a5.jpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week on Hafta, &lt;em&gt;Newslaundry&lt;/em&gt;’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Manisha Pande, and Shardool Katyayan are joined by Akshay Bhambri, doctoral fellow at the Institute for Chinese Studies–Harvard Yenching Institute, and Sumeet Mhaskar, professor at OP Jindal Global University.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The conversation opens with Prime Minister Narendra Modi’s visit to China for the SCO Summit – his first visit to the country since 2018 – where he held talks with Chinese President Xi Jinping and Russian President Vladimir Putin. The panel analyses the optics of the meeting, body language narratives, and India’s strategic balancing act.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Akshay argues that the Indian media’s portrayal of Chinese reactions is not actually correct, noting that Chinese social media largely framed Modi’s presence through Xi’s success in convening world leaders rather than admiration for Modi himself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;The Times of India&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Print&lt;/em&gt; reported that Putin and Modi’s car ride was trending on Baidu, China’s equivalent of Google. It did appear in the top 20 of Baidu’s trending list, but the conversation wasn’t really about appreciating Modi or his actions. Instead, users were more focused on how Trump might react, what this meant for Putin, and how Xi Jinping had managed to orchestrate the moment,” says Bhambri.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He also questions PM Modi’s visit with Chinese Foreign Minister Wang Yi.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“A big negative coming from SCO is that Modi met the right hand of Xi Jinping, Wang Yee, and all these people. When a head like the Prime Minister and president of China are meeting each other, there was no point meeting a second right hand of Xi Jinping, because that's a level below Xi Jinping.” Bhambri adds.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abhinandan adds, “The challenge for the Indian leadership is that Trump’s unpredictability has forced everyone to realign their positions. He has shaken up the global order so dramatically that confusion is inevitable.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking on India’s foreign policy, Manisha points out, “Indian diplomats and India’s foreign policy also have a lot to answer for, because they relied too much on the supposed personal chemistry of Modi with global leaders. Serious diplomats, or mandarins as they’re called, should have calculated what could happen and what needed to be done as situations evolved. You have to work out your realignment in advance, because at the end of the day, this is a game of chess.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sumeet explains that social hierarchy plays a crucial role in how protests are treated. When dominant castes like the Marathas mobilise, the state response is far more restrained compared to how it would react if Muslims or Dalits staged similar demonstrations. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timecodes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:03:30– Headlines&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:11:59 - &lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;PM Modi at SCO, Tianjin&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:59:55- Maratha quota protest&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:36:56 - Akshay &amp;amp; Sumeet’s recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:43:10 - Letters&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:50:28 - Recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VCmV6yr5t1LHE77Xp5-cYhWrQSkhW3A8nix310MvRQU/edit?usp=sharing&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Produced by Amit Pandey with production assistant Ashish Anand and sound recordist Anil .&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hafta 552: Online gaming ban, Trump’s 50 per cent tariff on India </title>
      <description>This week on Hafta, Newslaundry’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Raman Kirpal, Jayashree Arunachalam, and Anand Vardhan are joined by economist and author Vivek Kaul and sports journalist Sharda Ugra.&amp;nbsp;The episode opens with a discussion on the recently enacted Promotion and Regulation of Online Gaming Bill, 2025, which seeks to promote e-sports, regulate digital platforms, and ban real-money games. Abhinandan asks Vivek if he views online gaming as gambling or not.&amp;nbsp;Vivek replies, “Even if you argue that it’s a game of skill – that you need to know the players, their performance, the pitch, the weather, and so on – the real question is whether people are actually treating it as a game of skill.”He further cites the government’s data, pointing out that 45 crore people are playing these games. With so many participants, he argued, it’s no longer a game of skill but has essentially turned into a game of chance.Discussing the Indian cricket team's jersey, Sharda notes that it is probably the most expensive real estate an advertiser can buy.&amp;nbsp; “But notice the kind of companies that were stepping in – new-age firms like FinTech or EdTech players trying to build credibility and public recognition. Big, established corporates weren’t lining up for it,” she says.&amp;nbsp;She adds that  it was everyone who was trying to give their brand and their company a certain respectability. “The cricket team jersey is the easiest way to do it.”&amp;nbsp;Adding to the discussion, Jayashree says, “For me, this [the Bill] is like wearing a helmet. You can argue that if people don’t want to wear one and risk dying, that’s their choice. But it’s really not; there’s a law that enforces helmet use for a reason. Similarly, you need a bit of legal paternalism here, at least to keep things in check.”The conversation then shifts to the recent US tariffs and their impact on the Indian economy. Responding to Abhinandan’s question on the media coverage of the issue, Vivek explains: “The media is right when it says  it's the Americans who will pay that tariff. But what they’re not telling the Indian audience is that our exports to the US, which are their imports, can easily be sourced from other countries instead.”Raman points out that campaigns promoting Swadeshi products have started in India to cope with the tariffs.Timecodes00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements00:05:44 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;00:13:19:18 - &amp;nbsp;Ban on Online Gaming00:48:32- Sharda’s recommendation00:50:13 - US’ tariff’s impact on India&amp;nbsp;01:25:30 - Vivek’s recommendations01:27:33 - Letters01:35:42 - RecommendationsCheck out previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters.Produced by Amit Pandey with production assistant Ashish Anand and sound recordist Anil .&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <link>https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast/nl-hafta</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2025 05:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://feeds.acast.com/public/streams/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/episodes/68b29324993d10acb9ec45cc.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="6435880"/>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:duration>01:44:45</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:image href="https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1756533479825-9434316c-e9ac-4a6f-8b3b-52e21cee8d58.jpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week on Hafta, &lt;em&gt;Newslaundry&lt;/em&gt;’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Raman Kirpal, Jayashree Arunachalam, and Anand Vardhan are joined by economist and author Vivek Kaul and sports journalist Sharda Ugra.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The episode opens with a discussion on the recently enacted Promotion and Regulation of Online Gaming Bill, 2025, which seeks to promote e-sports, regulate digital platforms, and ban real-money games. Abhinandan asks Vivek if he views online gaming as gambling or not.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vivek replies, “Even if you argue that it’s a game of skill – that you need to know the players, their performance, the pitch, the weather, and so on – the real question is whether people are actually treating it as a game of skill.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He further cites the government’s data, pointing out that 45 crore people are playing these games. With so many participants, he argued, it’s no longer a game of skill but has essentially turned into a game of chance.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Discussing the Indian cricket team's jersey, Sharda notes that it is probably the most expensive real estate an advertiser can buy.&amp;nbsp; “But notice the kind of companies that were stepping in – new-age firms like FinTech or EdTech players trying to build credibility and public recognition. Big, established corporates weren’t lining up for it,” she says.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She adds that  it was everyone who was trying to give their brand and their company a certain respectability. “The cricket team jersey is the easiest way to do it.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Adding to the discussion, Jayashree says, “For me, this [the Bill] is like wearing a helmet. You can argue that if people don’t want to wear one and risk dying, that’s their choice. But it’s really not; there’s a law that enforces helmet use for a reason. Similarly, you need a bit of legal paternalism here, at least to keep things in check.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The conversation then shifts to the recent US tariffs and their impact on the Indian economy. Responding to Abhinandan’s question on the media coverage of the issue, Vivek explains: “The media is right when it says  it's the Americans who will pay that tariff. But what they’re not telling the Indian audience is that our exports to the US, which are their imports, can easily be sourced from other countries instead.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Raman points out that campaigns promoting Swadeshi products have started in India to cope with the tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timecodes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:05:44 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:13:19:18 - &lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/strong&gt;Ban on Online Gaming&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:48:32- Sharda’s recommendation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:50:13 - US’ tariff’s impact on India&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:25:30 - Vivek’s recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:27:33 - Letters&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:35:42 - Recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VCmV6yr5t1LHE77Xp5-cYhWrQSkhW3A8nix310MvRQU/edit?usp=sharing&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Produced by Amit Pandey with production assistant Ashish Anand and sound recordist Anil .&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hafta 551: Constitution 130th Amendment Bill, thaw in India-China relationship, Alaska meeting</title>
      <description>This week on Hafta, Newslaundry’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Manisha Pande, Raman Kirpal, and Shardool Katyayan are joined by Faizan Mustafa, legal scholar and VC of Chanakya National Law University, Patna, and Anuradha M Chenoy, former dean of JNU’s School of International Affairs.&amp;nbsp;The episode opens with a discussion on the Constitution (130th Amendment) Bill, 2025, recently introduced in Parliament by the government. Abhinandan asks Faizan whether the BJP will be able to get the bill passed in Parliament. Faizan responds that since it’s a constitutional amendment requiring a two-thirds majority in Parliament, which the current government doesn’t have, the Bill is unlikely to be passed.&amp;nbsp;Raman questioned the intent behind the bill. He said, “The intent of the government is very clear that they have initiated several corruption cases against politicians whom they don’t like and who fall out of favour, but yet they’re not able to tame them. Since 2014, there have been 193 cases against politicians. Only two convictions have happened. So now the judiciary decides whether a corruption case is right or wrong,” he added.Manisha adds, “I think to me, it's very clear in the tradition of countries like China, Russia, Turkey, Egypt, where anti-corruption laws are used to crack down on rivals…And the BJP should worry about it because in these countries, which have no democracy, which have authoritarian leadership, once they're done with opposition, they use these laws to crack down on rivals within the party. So the BJP should also worry because this is not just about the opposition.”The conversation then shifts to the recent Alaska Summit, where Russian and US presidents Vladimir Putin and Donald Trump met to discuss the ongoing Russo-Ukrainian War. Abhinandan asks Anuradha about the significance of the meeting: “Are you at all optimistic about this, or do you think it’s just optics and everything will stay the same?”Anuradha responds that the optimism comes from the fact that conversations and diplomacy are continuing. “In any war, especially in a situation where there has been a kind of cold war between Russia, Europe, and the US for years, this dialogue is significant. None of them had met over the last three years since Russia’s 2022 aggression on Ukraine, during which a proxy war had been underway.”The optimism, she explains, lies in the fact that they are now meeting and negotiating. “There will, of course, be disagreements, but as long as they don’t return to the old system of not engaging at all, there’s room for hope,” she adds.Shardool joins the discussion, pointing out that with China backing Russia, they don’t really have to worry about the United States.&amp;nbsp;“Also, the European Union cannot go against the US because its entire security structure is heavily dependent on American support – from troops to military machinery,” Shardool remarked.&amp;nbsp;Timecodes00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements00:03:06 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;00:10:25 - 130 th Amendment Bill 202500:43:43- Faizan’s recommendations00:48:54 - India &amp;amp; China relation &amp;amp; Alaska summit01:17:11 - Anuradha’s recommendations01:18:32 - Letters01:33:34 - RecommendationsCheck out previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters.Produced and recorded by Amit Pandey , Ashish Anand and Naresh.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <link>https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast/nl-hafta</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Aug 2025 06:13:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://feeds.acast.com/public/streams/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/episodes/68a95bef718453410e9471e3.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="6211133"/>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:duration>01:41:05</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:image href="https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1755929429929-b9f83747-6262-497d-ab16-bf4fbafc93ca.jpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week on Hafta, &lt;em&gt;Newslaundry&lt;/em&gt;’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Manisha Pande, Raman Kirpal, and Shardool Katyayan are joined by Faizan Mustafa, legal scholar and VC of Chanakya National Law University, Patna, and Anuradha M Chenoy, former dean of JNU’s School of International Affairs.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The episode opens with a discussion on the Constitution (130th Amendment) Bill, 2025, recently introduced in Parliament by the government. Abhinandan asks Faizan whether the BJP will be able to get the bill passed in Parliament. Faizan responds that since it’s a constitutional amendment requiring a two-thirds majority in Parliament, which the current government doesn’t have, the Bill is unlikely to be passed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Raman questioned the intent behind the bill. He said, “The intent of the government is very clear that they have initiated several corruption cases against politicians whom they don’t like and who fall out of favour, but yet they’re not able to tame them. Since 2014, there have been 193 cases against politicians. Only two convictions have happened. So now the judiciary decides whether a corruption case is right or wrong,” he added.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Manisha adds, “I think to me, it's very clear in the tradition of countries like China, Russia, Turkey, Egypt, where anti-corruption laws are used to crack down on rivals…And the BJP should worry about it because in these countries, which have no democracy, which have authoritarian leadership, once they're done with opposition, they use these laws to crack down on rivals within the party. So the BJP should also worry because this is not just about the opposition.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The conversation then shifts to the recent Alaska Summit, where Russian and US presidents Vladimir Putin and Donald Trump met to discuss the ongoing Russo-Ukrainian War. Abhinandan asks Anuradha about the significance of the meeting: “Are you at all optimistic about this, or do you think it’s just optics and everything will stay the same?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anuradha responds that the optimism comes from the fact that conversations and diplomacy are continuing. “In any war, especially in a situation where there has been a kind of cold war between Russia, Europe, and the US for years, this dialogue is significant. None of them had met over the last three years since Russia’s 2022 aggression on Ukraine, during which a proxy war had been underway.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The optimism, she explains, lies in the fact that they are now meeting and negotiating. “There will, of course, be disagreements, but as long as they don’t return to the old system of not engaging at all, there’s room for hope,” she adds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shardool joins the discussion, pointing out that with China backing Russia, they don’t really have to worry about the United States.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Also, the European Union cannot go against the US because its entire security structure is heavily dependent on American support – from troops to military machinery,” Shardool remarked.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timecodes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:03:06 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:10:25 - 130 th Amendment Bill 2025&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:43:43- Faizan’s recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:48:54 - India &amp;amp; China relation &amp;amp; Alaska summit&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:17:11 - Anuradha’s recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:18:32 - Letters&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:33:34 - Recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VCmV6yr5t1LHE77Xp5-cYhWrQSkhW3A8nix310MvRQU/edit?usp=sharing&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Produced and recorded by Amit Pandey , Ashish Anand and Naresh.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hafta 550: Opposition’s protest against Bihar SIR, SC’s stray dogs order, and Uttrakashi floods </title>
      <description>This week on Hafta, Newslaundry’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Manisha Pande, and Jayashree Arunachalam are joined by Priya Sahgal, editorial director at NewsX, Jasmine Damkewala, advocate on record in the Supreme Court, and senior journalist Hridayesh Joshi.The episode opens with a discussion on the opposition’s protest against the special intensive revision (SIR) exercise in Bihar. Priya states that when the opposition sets aside its differences, it can make an impact. “The fact that everybody came together, even the AAP, even though they're not part of the India Block itself, also showed there is unity. When the opposition comes in full strength, they can make an impact and a difference,” she says.&amp;nbsp;Referring to Rahul Gandhi’s press conference on alleged voter fraud, Manisha notes how it is unusual for a political party to assume the role traditionally played by the media. “However journalistically sound it may be or not be, it’s still striking that political parties today also have to do the media’s job of starting a narrative through such investigations, because very few organisations have actually invested time in looking into this issue and the related complaints.”The conversation then shifts to the Supreme Court’s order to remove stray dogs from Delhi’s streets. Jasmine Damkewala notes that the dog population surged during the pandemic, when government-led sterilisation drives came to a halt. “Especially during COVID, no sterilisations were happening, or very little… The thing is, the state government is not really doing sterilisations. They do very little, and for that, too, they send the dogs to NGOs and pay them for it.”&amp;nbsp;Manisha adds that the court’s solution seems unworkable as there aren’t enough shelters to house the dogs. “This is Delhi – we haven’t even figured out shelters for humans during extreme heat waves or extreme cold waves,” she says.Abhinandan agrees and says, “For the Supreme Court to pass an order that is unimplementable is ridiculous. We have to acknowledge there’s a problem, but this is certainly not the solution.”For the discussion on the Uttarakhand disaster, Hridayesh joins from ground zero. He recounts his journey to the site of the tragedy, despite being denied permission by the local authorities. He also discussed the current situation at Dharali, the village most affected by the flood.&amp;nbsp;Check out the Newslaundry store and flaunt your love for independent media.&amp;nbsp;Download the Newslaundry app.&amp;nbsp;Timecodes00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements00:05:46 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;00:16:47 - Opposition’s protest &amp;amp; INDIA bloc unity00:44:31- Priya’s recommendations00:47:53 - SC’s decision on stray dogs&amp;nbsp;01:11:04 - Updates on Uttarkashi disaster01:24:27- Letters01:33:40- RecommendationsCheck out previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters.Produced and recorded by Amit Pandey and Naresh.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <link>https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast/nl-hafta</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 05:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://feeds.acast.com/public/streams/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/episodes/68a01cda290bdec8f9c1ba77.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="6550405"/>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:duration>01:46:36</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:image href="https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1755323461718-711428f9-0a71-4e3a-910e-69d08576fba8.jpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week on Hafta, &lt;em&gt;Newslaundry&lt;/em&gt;’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Manisha Pande, and Jayashree Arunachalam are joined by Priya Sahgal, editorial director at &lt;em&gt;NewsX&lt;/em&gt;, Jasmine Damkewala, advocate on record in the Supreme Court, and senior journalist Hridayesh Joshi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The episode opens with a discussion on the opposition’s protest against the special intensive revision (SIR) exercise in Bihar. Priya states that when the opposition sets aside its differences, it can make an impact. “The fact that everybody came together, even the AAP, even though they're not part of the India Block itself, also showed there is unity. When the opposition comes in full strength, they can make an impact and a difference,” she says.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Referring to Rahul Gandhi’s press conference on alleged voter fraud, Manisha notes how it is unusual for a political party to assume the role traditionally played by the media. “However journalistically sound it may be or not be, it’s still striking that political parties today also have to do the media’s job of starting a narrative through such investigations, because very few organisations have actually invested time in looking into this issue and the related complaints.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The conversation then shifts to the Supreme Court’s order to remove stray dogs from Delhi’s streets. Jasmine Damkewala notes that the dog population surged during the pandemic, when government-led sterilisation drives came to a halt. “Especially during COVID, no sterilisations were happening, or very little… The thing is, the state government is not really doing sterilisations. They do very little, and for that, too, they send the dogs to NGOs and pay them for it.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Manisha adds that the court’s solution seems unworkable as there aren’t enough shelters to house the dogs. “This is Delhi – we haven’t even figured out shelters for humans during extreme heat waves or extreme cold waves,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abhinandan agrees and says, “For the Supreme Court to pass an order that is unimplementable is ridiculous. We have to acknowledge there’s a problem, but this is certainly not the solution.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the discussion on the Uttarakhand disaster, Hridayesh joins from ground zero. He recounts his journey to the site of the tragedy, despite being denied permission by the local authorities. He also discussed the current situation at Dharali, the village most affected by the flood.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out the&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newslaundry.com/store?routeName=NlStore&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; Newslaundry store&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and flaunt your love for independent media.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Download the&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newslaundry.com/download-app&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; Newslaundry app&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timecodes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:05:46 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:16:47 - Opposition’s protest &amp;amp; INDIA bloc unity&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:44:31- Priya’s recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:47:53 - SC’s decision on stray dogs&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:11:04 - Updates on Uttarkashi disaster&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:24:27- Letters&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:33:40- Recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VCmV6yr5t1LHE77Xp5-cYhWrQSkhW3A8nix310MvRQU/edit?usp=sharing&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Produced and recorded by Amit Pandey and Naresh.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hafta 549: Trump’s 50 per cent tariff threat on India, Uttarkashi disaster </title>
      <description>This week on Hafta, Newslaundry’s Manisha Pande, Jayashree Arunachalam, and Shardool Katyayan are joined by Nitin Pai, co-founder and director of The Takshashila Institution, and senior journalist Hridayesh Joshi from Uttarkashi.&amp;nbsp;The episode opens with a discussion on Trump’s recent announcement to double the tariff on India, from 25 percent to 50 percent. Nitin argued that there is nothing wrong with India buying oil from Russia.&amp;nbsp;He said, “ I don’t think there’s anything wrong in India buying oil from Russia or from Iran or from wherever, as long as we can get away with it. To claim that, 'Oh, you're buying gas from a country which is at war and you're killing' is absurd… If the yardstick is that you're supplying or buying from people who are killing others, then the United States has to sanction itself to death.&quot;Manisha asks Nitin what India should do next.&amp;nbsp;Despite the current tensions, including the imposition of steep tariffs by Trump and the broader uncertainty in US-India relations, Nitin underlines a crucial strategic point: that the United States remains India’s most important partner for long-term growth and development.“Even after all of this, the United States is still India’s best partner for growth and development. We've got to work with these guys and figure out how we can make use of the US economy and US military power to help us grow and be secure.” Nitin said.He further added that it would be foolish to talk about retaliation or going to the other side and forming an anti-US bloc. The answer is not in Moscow or Beijing – the answer is still in New Delhi.For the discussion on the Uttarkashi disaster, Hridayesh joined the discussion from ground zero.&amp;nbsp;Hridayesh said that the death toll in the incident could increase as the rescue operation unfolds. He asserted that this disaster is not the result of the cloud bursts.&amp;nbsp;“According to the definition [of cloudbursts], you require a hundred millimeters of rainfall in one hour in a particular area. So it has not happened [in Uttarkashi]. And, the other theories that are coming in say that there may be some obstruction in the upper reaches, and it may have formed a temporary lake. And that lake burst because of some landslide from above or by its own volume or pressure because it was raining continuously.” Hridayesh added.&amp;nbsp;Manisha added that the Uttarakhand government’s focus should be on such national disasters, but their priority instead is ‘Land Jihad’, ‘Love Jihad’, and registration of live-in relationships.&amp;nbsp;Shardool added that you can negotiate with every human problem, but you cannot negotiate with nature. “Like an overflowing river, it does not care who you are and what you are, and what your problems are. Nature is very brutal in its judgment,” he said. Timecodes00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements00:03:00 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;00:08:11-Trump’s Tariff threat to India&amp;nbsp;00:43:43- Nitin’s recommendations00:44:49 - Uttarkashi disaster&amp;nbsp;01:05:54- Letters01:20:35- RecommendationsCheck out previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters.Produced and recorded by Amit Pandey, Ashish Anand and Anil Kumar.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <link>https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast/nl-hafta</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Aug 2025 06:09:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://feeds.acast.com/public/streams/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/episodes/6896e63186fca1362897e0b4.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="5398541"/>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:duration>01:27:52</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:image href="https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1754718625695-4c3986f8-e3b1-4854-ab24-52e232f156a9.jpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week on Hafta, &lt;em&gt;Newslaundry&lt;/em&gt;’s Manisha Pande, Jayashree Arunachalam, and Shardool Katyayan are joined by Nitin Pai, co-founder and director of The Takshashila Institution, and senior journalist &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:hridayesh.joshi@gmail.com&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Hridayesh Joshi&lt;/a&gt; from Uttarkashi.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The episode opens with a discussion on Trump’s recent announcement to double the tariff on India, from 25 percent to 50 percent. Nitin argued that there is nothing wrong with India buying oil from Russia.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He said, “ I don’t think there’s anything wrong in India buying oil from Russia or from Iran or from wherever, as long as we can get away with it. To claim that, 'Oh, you're buying gas from a country which is at war and you're killing' is absurd… If the yardstick is that you're supplying or buying from people who are killing others, then the United States has to sanction itself to death.&quot;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Manisha asks Nitin what India should do next.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the current tensions, including the imposition of steep tariffs by Trump and the broader uncertainty in US-India relations, Nitin underlines a crucial strategic point: that the United States remains India’s most important partner for long-term growth and development.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Even after all of this, the United States is still India’s best partner for growth and development. We've got to work with these guys and figure out how we can make use of the US economy and US military power to help us grow and be secure.” Nitin said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He further added that it would be foolish to talk about retaliation or going to the other side and forming an anti-US bloc. The answer is not in Moscow or Beijing – the answer is still in New Delhi.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the discussion on the Uttarkashi disaster, Hridayesh joined the discussion from ground zero.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hridayesh said that the death toll in the incident could increase as the rescue operation unfolds. He asserted that this disaster is not the result of the cloud bursts.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“According to the definition [of cloudbursts], you require a hundred millimeters of rainfall in one hour in a particular area. So it has not happened [in Uttarkashi]. And, the other theories that are coming in say that there may be some obstruction in the upper reaches, and it may have formed a temporary lake. And that lake burst because of some landslide from above or by its own volume or pressure because it was raining continuously.” Hridayesh added.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Manisha added that the Uttarakhand government’s focus should be on such national disasters, but their priority instead is ‘Land Jihad’, ‘Love Jihad’, and registration of live-in relationships.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shardool added that you can negotiate with every human problem, but you cannot negotiate with nature. “Like an overflowing river, it does not care who you are and what you are, and what your problems are. Nature is very brutal in its judgment,” he said. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timecodes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:03:00 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:08:11-Trump’s Tariff threat to India&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:43:43- Nitin’s recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:44:49 - Uttarkashi disaster&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:05:54- Letters&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:20:35- Recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VCmV6yr5t1LHE77Xp5-cYhWrQSkhW3A8nix310MvRQU/edit?usp=sharing&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Produced and recorded by Amit Pandey, Ashish Anand and Anil Kumar.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hafta 548: Debate wars in Parliament, Trump’s tariffs on India </title>
      <description>This week on Hafta, Newslaundry’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Manisha Pande and Raman Kirpal are joined by Udit Misra from The Indian Express and independent journalist Sanjeev Srivastava.&amp;nbsp;The panel discusses the debates in Parliament on Operation Sindoor and the Pahalgam attack. Sanjeev says what stood out was Priyanka Gandhi Vadra’s “insistence of accountability”, calling it the “strongest point in her speech”. Raman praises some of the Congress leaders for raising strong questions.&amp;nbsp;Manisha says news channels celebrated Modi’s speech in Parliament, using tickers like “showshopper operation” and “PM’s big speech”. “It was a nothing speech and it should be called out for that,” she says. She also deplores the fact that there’s still no detail on what happened in Pahalgam and says the public needs “correct information and clarity”.Udit then explains Trump’s new tariffs on India. “Trump is not necessarily a free market ideologue. In his head, it’s a zero-sum game,” he says. “He wants zero deficit. That can happen when you and I don’t trade at all.”Abhinandan sums up India’s failed outreach to Trump as “Modi’s whole diplomacy effort”, pointing out that “all the airtime wasted in telling us how close we are” finally came to this.&amp;nbsp;This and a lot more. Tune in!Timecodes00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements00:04:45 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;00:13:21-Parliament debate on Op Sindoor&amp;amp;Pahalgam attack00:41:46- Sanjeev’s recommendations00:43:38- Trump imposes tariff on India-01:16:29 - Udit’s recommendations01:20:40- Letters01:28:5- RecommendationsCheck out previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters.Produced and recorded by Amit Pandey, Ashish Anand and Anil Kumar.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <link>https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast/nl-hafta</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Aug 2025 06:04:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://feeds.acast.com/public/streams/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/episodes/688daa6fc6d705dd3add5c90.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="5960815"/>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:duration>01:37:01</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:image href="https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1754114246586-b12a7b0a-e901-4b1b-aa48-d73b62189c6d.jpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week on Hafta, &lt;em&gt;Newslaundry&lt;/em&gt;’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Manisha Pande and Raman Kirpal are joined by Udit Misra from &lt;em&gt;The Indian Express&lt;/em&gt; and independent journalist Sanjeev Srivastava.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The panel discusses the debates in Parliament on Operation Sindoor and the Pahalgam attack. Sanjeev says what stood out was Priyanka Gandhi Vadra’s “insistence of accountability”, calling it the “strongest point in her speech”. Raman praises some of the Congress leaders for raising strong questions.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Manisha says news channels celebrated Modi’s speech in Parliament, using tickers like “showshopper operation” and “PM’s big speech”. “It was a nothing speech and it should be called out for that,” she says. She also deplores the fact that there’s still no detail on what happened in Pahalgam and says the public needs “correct information and clarity”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Udit then explains Trump’s new tariffs on India. “Trump is not necessarily a free market ideologue. In his head, it’s a zero-sum game,” he says. “He wants zero deficit. That can happen when you and I don’t trade at all.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Abhinandan sums up India’s failed outreach to Trump as “Modi’s whole diplomacy effort”, pointing out that “all the airtime wasted in telling us how close we are” finally came to this.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This and a lot more. Tune in!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timecodes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:04:45 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:13:21-Parliament debate on Op Sindoor&amp;amp;Pahalgam attack&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:41:46- Sanjeev’s recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:43:38- Trump imposes tariff on India-&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:16:29 - Udit’s recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:20:40- Letters&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:28:5- Recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VCmV6yr5t1LHE77Xp5-cYhWrQSkhW3A8nix310MvRQU/edit?usp=sharing&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Produced and recorded by Amit Pandey, Ashish Anand and Anil Kumar.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hafta 547 :‘Paranoia’ in Modi govt, FTA myth, and an old police playbook</title>
      <description>This week on Hafta, Newslaundry’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Anand Vardhan, Raman Kirpal, and Jayashree Arunachalam are joined by MK Venu, Founding Editor of The Wire, and award-winning investigative journalist and author Josy Joseph.The panel begins with a discussion on the recently signed “historic” India-UK free trade agreement. Venu argues that the BJP’s intention behind this FTA is to have a “fresh start” in global trade negotiations: “In the last 11 years of the Modi government, the narrative they built, led by Piyush Goyal, is that all the FTAs signed by the UPA government were bad for India, that they were being used as a conduit for Chinese goods.”The conversation then shifts to Jagdeep Dhankhar’s resignation as vice president. Abhinandan asks who will oversee the Rajya Sabha “with the parliament session already happening, and all sorts of noise and protests”.Explaining the legal framework, Anand says, “Article 67 says that till the next vice president is appointed, he will have to continue. But he has made it clear that he will not be attending the House.”&amp;nbsp;Venu draws a pattern of abrupt and unexplained resignations among the Indian political and bureaucratic elite: “There is a striking parallel in the manner in which Dhankhar, CBI chief (former Director) Alok Verma, and (former Election Commissioner) Arun Goel abruptly left. What is it that drives leadership in the Modi-Shah regime? There’s intrigue, there’s cloak and dagger, there’s paranoia. Paranoia accompanied by complete power. It’s a paradox.”Commenting on media speculation around Dhankhar’s resignation, Anand says, “Journalists and public and social media commentators cannot say the simple thing that ‘we don’t know’.” Jayashree adds, “It doesn’t matter if there is any value to these theories. What matters is that you have a story,&amp;nbsp;a source, the source has said something outlandish, and that is your headline.”The panel then shifts to the Bombay High Court’s recent verdict on the 2006 Mumbai blasts. Raman explains: “It’s a 576-page judgement talking about how the police have manufactured evidence in very great detail…This particular judgement has put a huge question mark on this state-specific law MCOCA.”Drawing from his decades of experience reporting on intelligence and security, Josy says: “One of the things that has always struck me was the impunity with which our police and investigative agencies are able to do pure malicious things and get away because there is no prosecution for malpractices.”Josy also sheds light on the complexities of police functioning and the political pressures that often influence investigations. “I think in India today, the most difficult job is not being a journalist or not being an NGO worker. I think the most difficult job is to be an honest government official.”Timecodes00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements00:05:50 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;00:14:20-FTA Deal between UK &amp;amp; India / VP’s resignation00:47:55- MK Venu’s recommendations00:54:02 - Bombay Blast acquittal by the HC01:21:30 - Josy’s Recommendation01:27:33- Letters01:43:40- RecommendationsCheck out previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters.Produced and recorded by Amit Pandey, Ashish Anand and Anil Kumar.&amp;nbsp;Research assistance by Vibha Rajeev.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <link>https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast/nl-hafta</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2025 06:04:26 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://feeds.acast.com/public/streams/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/episodes/68846febf6d4262b07ad9bbb.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="6926628"/>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:duration>01:52:44</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:image href="https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1753508850231-7ebaf7c6-18f8-42c4-9203-6bd38d22e9d2.jpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This week on Hafta, &lt;em&gt;Newslaundry&lt;/em&gt;’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Anand Vardhan, Raman Kirpal, and Jayashree Arunachalam are joined by MK Venu, Founding Editor of &lt;em&gt;The Wire&lt;/em&gt;, and award-winning investigative journalist and author Josy Joseph.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The panel begins with a discussion on the recently signed “historic” India-UK free trade agreement. Venu argues that the BJP’s intention behind this FTA is to have a “fresh start” in global trade negotiations: “In the last 11 years of the Modi government, the narrative they built, led by Piyush Goyal, is that all the FTAs signed by the UPA government were bad for India, that they were being used as a conduit for Chinese goods.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The conversation then shifts to Jagdeep Dhankhar’s resignation as vice president. Abhinandan asks who will oversee the Rajya Sabha “with the parliament session already happening, and all sorts of noise and protests”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Explaining the legal framework, Anand says, “Article 67 says that till the next vice president is appointed, he will have to continue. But he has made it clear that he will not be attending the House.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Venu draws a pattern of abrupt and unexplained resignations among the Indian political and bureaucratic elite: “There is a striking parallel in the manner in which Dhankhar, CBI chief (former Director) Alok Verma, and (former Election Commissioner) Arun Goel abruptly left. What is it that drives leadership in the Modi-Shah regime? There’s intrigue, there’s cloak and dagger, there’s paranoia. Paranoia accompanied by complete power. It’s a paradox.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Commenting on media speculation around Dhankhar’s resignation, Anand says, “Journalists and public and social media commentators cannot say the simple thing that ‘we don’t know’.” Jayashree adds, “It doesn’t matter if there is any value to these theories. What matters is that you have a story,&amp;nbsp;a source, the source has said something outlandish, and that is your headline.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The panel then shifts to the Bombay High Court’s recent verdict on the 2006 Mumbai blasts. Raman explains: “It’s a 576-page judgement talking about how the police have manufactured evidence in very great detail…This particular judgement has put a huge question mark on this state-specific law MCOCA.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Drawing from his decades of experience reporting on intelligence and security, Josy says: “One of the things that has always struck me was the impunity with which our police and investigative agencies are able to do pure malicious things and get away because there is no prosecution for malpractices.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Josy also sheds light on the complexities of police functioning and the political pressures that often influence investigations. “I think in India today, the most difficult job is not being a journalist or not being an NGO worker. I think the most difficult job is to be an honest government official.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timecodes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:05:50 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:14:20-FTA Deal between UK &amp;amp; India / VP’s resignation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:47:55- MK Venu’s recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:54:02 - Bombay Blast acquittal by the HC&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:21:30 - Josy’s Recommendation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:27:33- Letters&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:43:40- Recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VCmV6yr5t1LHE77Xp5-cYhWrQSkhW3A8nix310MvRQU/edit?usp=sharing&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Produced and recorded by Amit Pandey, Ashish Anand and Anil Kumar.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Research assistance by Vibha Rajeev.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hafta 546: The performance of authority on social media, FIR against Ajit Anjum and Bihar SIR</title>
      <description>This week on Hafta, Newslaundry’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Manisha Pande, Raman Kirpal, and Shardool Katyayan are joined by University of Michigan’s Associate Professor Joyojeet Pal and senior journalist Radhika Ramaseshan.&amp;nbsp;The episode opens with a discussion on Joyojeet and his team’s research on the persuasion strategies used by social media influencers to talk about the benefits of cow urine.“One of the most interesting things we noticed was the use of scientific terminology by influencers who talk about cow urine. They say things like ‘it has phosphorus,’ or ‘it releases dopamine.’ These are not verified claims. But the point isn’t whether they’re true. It’s about the performance of authority — using science-y language to sound legitimate,” Joyojeet says.&amp;nbsp;Shifting to Bihar’s controversial Special Intensive Revision (SIR) exercise, Radhika points out that in many places of Bihar, BLOs are signing for the missing voters.&amp;nbsp;She remarks, “I don’t believe this is a random or routine process. It appears to be targeted, focused on constituencies where the ruling alliance anticipates a weaker performance.”Echoing her concerns, Raman added, “It’s supposed to be an intensive verification exercise, but that’s clearly not what’s happening in practice.”Referring to the recent FIR against journalist Ajit Anjum, Abhinandan points to a troubling trend, “The nature of FIRs launched against journalists in the country is laughable. I don’t know if the police expect the citizens to take them seriously.”Manisha calls out the BJP’s repeated and unproven claims of Bangladeshi and Rohingya voters in Bihar constituencies and says, “They create this perpetual state of insecurity and panic before elections. This seems to be one of BJP’s key electoral strategies.”&amp;nbsp;Timecodes00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements00:02:47 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;00:15:43-How influencers promote cow urine00:47:39- Joyjeet’s recommendations00:49:021 - Bihar Special Intensive Revision01:10:32- Letters01:26:29- RecommendationsCheck out previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters.Produced and recorded by Amit Pandey, Ashish Anand and Anil Kumar.&amp;nbsp;Research assistance by Vibha Rajeev&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <link>https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast/nl-hafta</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Jul 2025 06:24:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://feeds.acast.com/public/streams/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/episodes/687b3a34a2391fe43255eddb.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="5828842"/>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:duration>01:34:52</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:image href="https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1752905669521-a52fa6b6-a98c-464e-8c1e-7c6dd33ceab2.jpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week on Hafta, Newslaundry’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Manisha Pande, Raman Kirpal, and Shardool Katyayan are joined by University of Michigan’s Associate Professor Joyojeet Pal and senior journalist Radhika Ramaseshan.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The episode opens with a discussion on Joyojeet and his team’s research on the persuasion strategies used by social media influencers to talk about the benefits of cow urine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“One of the most interesting things we noticed was the use of scientific terminology by influencers who talk about cow urine. They say things like ‘it has phosphorus,’ or ‘it releases dopamine.’ These are not verified claims. But the point isn’t whether they’re true. It’s about the &lt;em&gt;performance&lt;/em&gt; of authority — using science-y language to sound legitimate,” Joyojeet says.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shifting to Bihar’s controversial Special Intensive Revision (SIR) exercise, Radhika points out that in many places of Bihar, BLOs are signing for the missing voters.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She remarks, “I don’t believe this is a random or routine process. It appears to be targeted, focused on constituencies where the ruling alliance anticipates a weaker performance.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Echoing her concerns, Raman added, “It’s supposed to be an intensive verification exercise, but that’s clearly not what’s happening in practice.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Referring to the recent FIR against journalist Ajit Anjum, Abhinandan points to a troubling trend, “The nature of FIRs launched against journalists in the country is laughable. I don’t know if the police expect the citizens to take them seriously.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Manisha calls out the BJP’s repeated and unproven claims of Bangladeshi and Rohingya voters in Bihar constituencies and says, “They create this perpetual state of insecurity and panic before elections. This seems to be one of BJP’s key electoral strategies.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timecodes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:02:47 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:15:43-How influencers promote cow urine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:47:39- Joyjeet’s recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:49:021 - Bihar Special Intensive Revision&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:10:32- Letters&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:26:29- Recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VCmV6yr5t1LHE77Xp5-cYhWrQSkhW3A8nix310MvRQU/edit?usp=sharing&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Produced and recorded by Amit Pandey, Ashish Anand and Anil Kumar.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Research assistance by Vibha Rajeev&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hafta 545: Bihar electoral revision, Dalai Lama and the future of Tibetan movement </title>
      <description>This week on Hafta, Newslaundry’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Jayashree Arunachalam, Anand Vardhan, and Shardool Katyayan are joined by election analyst and researcher Amitabh Tiwari, along with historian and Newslaundry subscriber Swati Chawla.The episode opens with the latest updates on Bihar’s electoral politics and the ongoing Special Intensive Revision. Amitabh Tiwari calls out the contradiction at the heart of the process: “If Aadhaar is not the citizenship proof, then how can Aadhaar alone be used to get enrolled as a voter?Anand adds, “Supreme Court's presidents and the judgments have made it clear that voting is&amp;nbsp; a statutory right, and not a fundamental one.”Jayashree highlights the logistical absurdity in demanding documents: “In Bihar, only 40 percent of births are registered. So, most of the population won't have a birth certificate.”Shardool sums it up: “It is the Home Ministry's job to identify citizens, not ECI's. ”He questions the pressure on ground staff: “Booth level officers who are junior level teachers in government schools have left all their jobs and distributed 98 percent voter roll forms, and they are now saying that we are updating it 10 percent every day to over 60 lakhs forms.”The panel also reflects on prohibition in Bihar, with many youth supporting it as a way to reduce crime in public spaces. The conversation then shifts to the Dalai Lama, who turned 90 this week. Swati explains China’s obsession: “Control succession is a way to control society.”&amp;nbsp;She slams Beijing’s state-appointed Panchen Lama as illegitimate and applauds India’s unwavering support: “No country has done more for the Dalai Lama and Tibetan exile than India has.” Shardool says, “I believe India should be more aggressive to support.” Abhinandan presses: “If it’s worked so well, why is China still insecure about the Dalai Lama?”Anand adds historical context: “China has a state memory since the Han dynasty of forcibly settling people to secure territory, like Tibet.”&amp;nbsp;On what Tibetans want, he explains, “The Dalai Lama wants meaningful autonomy within China – not independence.”This and a lot more. Tune in! Timecodes00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements00:04:04 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;00:16:08 -Bihar voter revision00:56:28 - Amitabh’s recommendations01:05:13 - Dalai Lama and future of Tibetan movement01:40:19- Letters01:49:31- RecommendationsCheck out previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters.Produced and recorded by Priyali Dhingra, Amit Pandey, and Anil Kumar.&amp;nbsp;Research assistance by Swastika Rajput.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <link>https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast/nl-hafta</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2025 06:07:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://feeds.acast.com/public/streams/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/episodes/6871fbafc8b2c1159de10c7f.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="7489639"/>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:duration>02:01:54</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:image href="https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1752300363150-aec573c7-4e7a-4d6b-9004-620e0647c8e3.jpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week on Hafta, &lt;em&gt;Newslaundry&lt;/em&gt;’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Jayashree Arunachalam, Anand Vardhan, and Shardool Katyayan are joined by election analyst and researcher Amitabh Tiwari, along with historian and Newslaundry subscriber Swati Chawla.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The episode opens with the latest updates on Bihar’s electoral politics and the ongoing Special Intensive Revision. Amitabh Tiwari calls out the contradiction at the heart of the process: “If Aadhaar is not the citizenship proof, then how can Aadhaar alone be used to get enrolled as a voter?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anand adds, “Supreme Court's presidents and the judgments have made it clear that voting is&amp;nbsp; a statutory right, and not a fundamental one.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jayashree highlights the logistical absurdity in demanding documents: “In Bihar, only 40 percent of births are registered. So, most of the population won't have a birth certificate.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shardool sums it up: “It is the Home Ministry's job to identify citizens, not ECI's. ”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He questions the pressure on ground staff: “Booth level officers who are junior level teachers in government schools have left all their jobs and distributed 98 percent voter roll forms, and they are now saying that we are updating it 10 percent every day to over 60 lakhs forms.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The panel also reflects on prohibition in Bihar, with many youth supporting it as a way to reduce crime in public spaces. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The conversation then shifts to the Dalai Lama, who turned 90 this week. Swati explains China’s obsession: “Control succession is a way to control society.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;She slams Beijing’s state-appointed Panchen Lama as illegitimate and applauds India’s unwavering support: “No country has done more for the Dalai Lama and Tibetan exile than India has.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shardool says, “I believe India should be more aggressive to support.” Abhinandan presses: “If it’s worked so well, why is China still insecure about the Dalai Lama?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anand adds historical context: “China has a state memory since the Han dynasty of forcibly settling people to secure territory, like Tibet.”&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On what Tibetans want, he explains, “The Dalai Lama wants meaningful autonomy within China – not independence.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This and a lot more. Tune in! &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timecodes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:04:04 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:16:08 -Bihar voter revision&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:56:28 - Amitabh’s recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:05:13 - Dalai Lama and future of Tibetan movement&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:40:19- Letters&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:49:31- Recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VCmV6yr5t1LHE77Xp5-cYhWrQSkhW3A8nix310MvRQU/edit?usp=sharing&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Produced and recorded by Priyali Dhingra, Amit Pandey, and Anil Kumar.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Research assistance by Swastika Rajput.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hafta 544 : India’s lost tourism potential, and floods in Himachal Pradesh and Uttarakhand</title>
      <description>This week on Hafta, Newslaundry’s Manisha Pande, Jayashree Arunachalam and Raman Kirpal&amp;nbsp;are joined by writer and economist Vivek Kaul and environmental journalist Hridayesh Joshi.&amp;nbsp;The episode begins with a discussion comparing India’s tourism landscape with that of Southeast Asian countries and why, despite its size, beauty and culture, India remains far behind its Asian neighbours as a global tourist destination.&amp;nbsp;Manisha draws comparisons with cleaner, better-maintained cities like Ho Chi Minh City and Bali, and questions why India continues to fall behind in basic urban infrastructure and tourist appeal.&amp;nbsp;Jayashree says, “India is unsafe for everyone. That’s why tourists are unsafe here.” Vivek adds, “In 2024, Bali got a little over 6 million foreign tourists. In 2023, they got over 5 million…Forget Goa, Bali probably gets as many tourists as all of India does.”On India’s cleanliness problem, Jayashree says: “Caste is the main driver of dirt. The wealthy produce the most waste and don’t care about where it goes.” Hridayesh says, “We dump solid waste into rivers; this happens with full knowledge of officials who take bribes.”On environmental degradation and the floods in Himachal Pradesh, Hridayesh warns, “We are doing everything to facilitate a disaster, not prevent one.” He explains how unchecked construction and poor planning turns natural hazards into man-made disasters.&amp;nbsp;This and a lot more. Tune in!We have a page for subscribers to send letters to our shows. If you want to write to Hafta, click here. And click here to contribute to our new Sena project.Check out the Newslaundry store and flaunt your love for independent media.&amp;nbsp;Download the Newslaundry app. 'Timecodes00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements00:05:06 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;00:13:44 - Tourism in India and why we are lagging behind00:57:58 - Floods in Himachal Pradesh and Uttarakhand01:31:41 - Letters01:45:23- RecommendationsCheck out previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters.Produced and recorded by Priyali Dhingra, Amit Pandey, and Anil Kumar.&amp;nbsp;Production and research assistance by Saurav Ranjan and Swastika Rajput.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <link>https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast/nl-hafta</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Jul 2025 06:12:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://feeds.acast.com/public/streams/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/episodes/6868c1f43b5dc9fc2237ce73.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="6864486"/>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:duration>01:51:43</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:image href="https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1751695551059-62a98700-bdf2-4588-911c-4f8f4d930ac3.jpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This week on Hafta, &lt;em&gt;Newslaundry&lt;/em&gt;’s Manisha Pande, Jayashree Arunachalam and Raman Kirpal&amp;nbsp;are joined by writer and economist Vivek Kaul and environmental journalist Hridayesh Joshi.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The episode begins with a discussion comparing India’s tourism landscape with that of Southeast Asian countries and why, despite its size, beauty and culture, India remains far behind its Asian neighbours as a global tourist destination.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Manisha draws comparisons with cleaner, better-maintained cities like Ho Chi Minh City and Bali, and questions why India continues to fall behind in basic urban infrastructure and tourist appeal.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jayashree says, “India is unsafe for everyone. That’s why tourists are unsafe here.” Vivek adds, “In 2024, Bali got a little over 6 million foreign tourists. In 2023, they got over 5 million…Forget Goa, Bali probably gets as many tourists as all of India does.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On India’s cleanliness problem, Jayashree says: “Caste is the main driver of dirt. The wealthy produce the most waste and don’t care about where it goes.” Hridayesh says, “We dump solid waste into rivers; this happens with full knowledge of officials who take bribes.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;On environmental degradation and the floods in Himachal Pradesh, Hridayesh warns, “We are doing everything to facilitate a disaster, not prevent one.” He explains how unchecked construction and poor planning turns natural hazards into man-made disasters.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This and a lot more. Tune in!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have a page for subscribers to send letters to our shows. If you want to write to Hafta, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast-letters&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;click here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. And click &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://newslaundry.com/sena&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; to contribute to our new Sena project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out the&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newslaundry.com/store?routeName=NlStore&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; Newslaundry store&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and flaunt your love for independent media.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Download the&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newslaundry.com/download-app&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; Newslaundry app&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. '&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timecodes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:05:06 – Headlines&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:13:44 - Tourism in India and why we are lagging behind&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:57:58 - Floods in Himachal Pradesh and Uttarakhand&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:31:41 - Letters&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:45:23- Recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VCmV6yr5t1LHE77Xp5-cYhWrQSkhW3A8nix310MvRQU/edit?usp=sharing&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Produced and recorded by Priyali Dhingra, Amit Pandey, and Anil Kumar.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Production and research assistance by Saurav Ranjan and Swastika Rajput.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hafta 543 : 50 years of Emergency, voter additions in Maharashtra, Karnataka’s new bills</title>
      <description>This week on Hafta, Newslaundry’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Jayashree Arunachalam, Raman Kirpal and Anand Vardhan are joined by senior journalist Neerja Chowdhury, The News Minute’s editor-in-chief Dhanya Rajendran, and Newslaundry reporter Sumedha Mittal.&amp;nbsp;This week marked the 50th anniversary of the Emergency and the central government’s commemoration of the event. Neerja says it was important, since most young Indians today weren’t alive during the Emergency and are unaware of its impact. But “have we learned lessons”, Abhinandan asks, and the panel has varying views.&amp;nbsp;Dhanya explains two new bills in Karnataka – one to tackle fake news, and the other criminalising hate speech. She talks about why both are problematic and what the Congress government in the state hopes to achieve.The panel then discusses Sumedha’s report from Nagpur, where she found over 29,200 new voters were curiously added to the electoral rolls in Devendra Fadnavis’s constituency. This Newslaundry investigation has triggered a political outcry in the state, and Sumedha explains why.This and a lot more. Tune in!We have a page for subscribers to send letters to our shows. If you want to write to Hafta, click here. And click here to contribute to our new Sena project.Check out the Newslaundry store and flaunt your love for independent media.&amp;nbsp;Download the Newslaundry app. Song: U96 - Das BootTimecodes00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements00:03:13– Headlines&amp;nbsp;00:10:35 - 50 years of Emergency and its media coverage&amp;nbsp;00:43:25- Karnataka Misinformation and Fake News (Prohibition) Bill01:08:38 - Voter additions in Maharashtra&amp;nbsp;01:21:03 - Letters01:26:52 - RecommendationsCheck out previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters.Produced and recorded by Ashish Anand, Amit Pandey and Anil Kumar.&amp;nbsp;Research assistance by Swastika Rajput.&amp;nbsp;Production assistance by Saurabh and Ankit Raj.</description>
      <link>https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast/nl-hafta</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Jun 2025 06:59:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://feeds.acast.com/public/streams/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/episodes/685f92bc653df36e7b1d4807.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="6066114"/>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:duration>01:38:43</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:image href="https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1751695551059-62a98700-bdf2-4588-911c-4f8f4d930ac3.jpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week on Hafta, &lt;em&gt;Newslaundry&lt;/em&gt;’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Jayashree Arunachalam, Raman Kirpal and Anand Vardhan are joined by senior journalist Neerja Chowdhury, &lt;em&gt;The News Minute&lt;/em&gt;’s editor-in-chief Dhanya Rajendran, and &lt;em&gt;Newslaundry &lt;/em&gt;reporter Sumedha Mittal.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This week marked the 50th anniversary of the Emergency and the central government’s commemoration of the event. Neerja says it was important, since most young Indians today weren’t alive during the Emergency and are unaware of its impact. But “have we learned lessons”, Abhinandan asks, and the panel has varying views.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dhanya explains two new bills in Karnataka – one to tackle fake news, and the other criminalising hate speech. She talks about why both are problematic and what the Congress government in the state hopes to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The panel then discusses Sumedha’s report from Nagpur, where she found over 29,200 new voters were curiously added to the electoral rolls in Devendra Fadnavis’s constituency. This &lt;em&gt;Newslaundry&lt;/em&gt; investigation has triggered a political outcry in the state, and Sumedha explains why.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This and a lot more. Tune in!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have a page for subscribers to send letters to our shows. If you want to write to Hafta, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast-letters&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;click here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. And click &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://newslaundry.com/sena&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; to contribute to our new Sena project.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out the&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newslaundry.com/store?routeName=NlStore&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; Newslaundry store&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and flaunt your love for independent media.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Download the&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newslaundry.com/download-app&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; Newslaundry app&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Song: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=JJk0PqiVBAE&amp;amp;t=84s&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;U96 - Das Boot&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timecodes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:03:13– Headlines&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:10:35 - 50 years of Emergency and its media coverage&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:43:25- Karnataka Misinformation and Fake News (Prohibition) Bill&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:08:38 - Voter additions in Maharashtra&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:21:03 - Letters&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:26:52 - Recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VCmV6yr5t1LHE77Xp5-cYhWrQSkhW3A8nix310MvRQU/edit?usp=sharing&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Produced and recorded by Ashish Anand, Amit Pandey and Anil Kumar.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Research assistance by Swastika Rajput.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Production assistance by Saurabh and Ankit Raj.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hafta 541: Air India crash, Manipur violence, covering crime stories </title>
      <description>This week on Hafta, Newslaundry’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Raman Kirpal, Manisha Pande, and Jayashree Arunachalam are joined by former Executive Director, Air India, Jitendra Bhargava, and Executive Editor of The Frontier Manipur, Paojel Choaba.&amp;nbsp; The episode begins with a discussion on the devastating Air India crash, where a Boeing 787 Dreamliner, carrying 242 passengers, crashed shortly after takeoff in Ahmedabad. Jitender adds, “The cockpit voice recorder and black box will decode what actually transpired between pilot and the co-pilot…and what, if anything, was said to the passengers in the last moments.” Manisha raises concerns about Boeing’s history, citing, “Boeing has actually just wrapped up a long legal case in the US where they’ve paid a billion dollars for two crashes,” though Bhargava counters, “The safety track record must prove what it is,” given the Dreamliner’s extensive operational history.The panel critiques the media’s handling, with Jayashree expressing dismay: “I thought it was quite upsetting… families had found out minutes ago just as the reporters were arriving.”The conversation shifts to Manipur’s ethnic conflict, with Paojel providing firsthand insights. He describes a tense peace, “The shooting has stopped, but the violence has become more internal in a way.” Over 60,000 people are displaced, and “more than 200 people have been killed.”Commenting on the President's rule, he adds, “While there has been some recovery of arms under the Governor's rule, there has been no concrete positive actions to restore normalcy. But law and order has improved.” The panel also discusses the murder case in Meghalaya dominating headlines throughout the week and the ethics of covering crime stories.&amp;nbsp;This and a lot more. Tune in!We have a page for subscribers to send letters to our shows. If you want to write to Hafta, click here.&amp;nbsp;Check out the Newslaundry store and flaunt your love for independent media.&amp;nbsp;Download the Newslaundry app. Timecodes00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements00:02:12– Headlines&amp;nbsp;00:06:51 - Air India crash00:45:28 - Announcements00:47:48 - Manipur violence01:17:31 - Meghalaya murder case and how crime stories should be covered01:29:47 - Letters&amp;nbsp;01:38:30 - RecommendationsCheck out previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters Produced by Priyali Dhingra and Amit Pandey. Recorded by Ashish Anand and Anil Kumar.&amp;nbsp;</description>
      <link>https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast/nl-hafta</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 07:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      <enclosure url="https://feeds.acast.com/public/streams/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/episodes/684d2017b903c43b04184f2c.mp3" type="audio/mpeg" length="6730895"/>
      <itunes:episodeType>full</itunes:episodeType>
      <itunes:duration>01:49:33</itunes:duration>
      <itunes:image href="https://assets.pippa.io/shows/5ec3d9497cef7479d2ef4798/1749884896956-52de8abc-0f60-4a83-83fd-513e922d515e.jpeg"/>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This week on Hafta, &lt;em&gt;Newslaundry&lt;/em&gt;’s Abhinandan Sekhri, Raman Kirpal, Manisha Pande, and Jayashree Arunachalam are joined by former Executive Director, Air India, Jitendra Bhargava, and Executive Editor of &lt;em&gt;The Frontier Manipur&lt;/em&gt;, Paojel Choaba.&amp;nbsp; &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The episode begins with a discussion on the devastating Air India crash, where a Boeing 787 Dreamliner, carrying 242 passengers, crashed shortly after takeoff in Ahmedabad. Jitender adds, “The cockpit voice recorder and black box will decode what actually transpired between pilot and the co-pilot…and what, if anything, was said to the passengers in the last moments.” Manisha raises concerns about Boeing’s history, citing, “Boeing has actually just wrapped up a long legal case in the US where they’ve paid a billion dollars for two crashes,” though Bhargava counters, “The safety track record must prove what it is,” given the Dreamliner’s extensive operational history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The panel critiques the media’s handling, with Jayashree expressing dismay: “I thought it was quite upsetting… families had found out minutes ago just as the reporters were arriving.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The conversation shifts to Manipur’s ethnic conflict, with Paojel providing firsthand insights. He describes a tense peace, “The shooting has stopped, but the violence has become more internal in a way.” Over 60,000 people are displaced, and “more than 200 people have been killed.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Commenting on the President's rule, he adds, “While there has been some recovery of arms under the Governor's rule, there has been no concrete positive actions to restore normalcy. But law and order has improved.” &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The panel also discusses the murder case in Meghalaya dominating headlines throughout the week and the ethics of covering crime stories.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This and a lot more. Tune in!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We have a page for subscribers to send letters to our shows. If you want to write to Hafta, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newslaundry.com/podcast-letters&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;click here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out the&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newslaundry.com/store?routeName=NlStore&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; Newslaundry store&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and flaunt your love for independent media.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Download the&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.newslaundry.com/download-app&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt; Newslaundry app&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Timecodes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:00:00 – Introductions and announcements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:02:12– Headlines&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:06:51 - Air India crash&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:45:28 - Announcements&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;00:47:48 - Manipur violence&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:17:31 - Meghalaya murder case and how crime stories should be covered&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:29:47 - Letters&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;01:38:30 - Recommendations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check out &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1VCmV6yr5t1LHE77Xp5-cYhWrQSkhW3A8nix310MvRQU/edit?usp=sharing&quot; rel=&quot;noopener noreferrer&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;previous Hafta recommendations, references, songs and letters&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Produced by Priyali Dhingra and Amit Pandey. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Recorded by Ashish Anand and Anil Kumar.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
